<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on weirdloop</title>
    <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on weirdloop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>weirdloop</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 06:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fish Shell: Creating and Sharing Packages with Oh My Fish</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/enhancing-fish-with-omf-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 06:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/enhancing-fish-with-omf-packages/</guid>
      <description>One of the aspects I personally find most compelling about fish shell is its scripting ease. Unlike traditional shells, fish&amp;rsquo;s scripting language is straightforward, clean, and comes with features that encourage writing and maintaining scripts effortlessly. From its intelligent autosuggestions to the robust error handling, fish shell stands out as a powerful tool in the developer&amp;rsquo;s toolkit.&#xA;With the integration of the Oh My Fish (OMF) framework, users can further extend the shell&amp;rsquo;s functionality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse Mosquitto: Leveraging Certificates for Encryption, Identification, and ACLs</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/mqtt_tls_acls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 06:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/mqtt_tls_acls/</guid>
      <description>This blog post delves into the sophisticated use of TLS certificates with Mosquitto, transcending their conventional role as encryption tools to serve as pivotal elements in client authentication and authorization.&#xA;We’ll explore how certificates, typically recognized for their role in securing communications, can be ingeniously repurposed for client identification through their Common Name (CN) attribute. This approach not only enhances the security posture of your MQTT ecosystem but also simplifies the authentication process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Again!</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 19:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>Yes, hello, again! I&amp;rsquo;m trying one more time to get a blog running and keep it up to date, writing about things that interest me. Hopefully, this time will be different and won&amp;rsquo;t be abandoned after a few posts :)&#xA;def hello(): print(&amp;#39;Hello, Again!&amp;#39;) </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
