<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>weirdloop</title>
    <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on weirdloop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>weirdloop</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 08:26:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://calvernaz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data-Only Containers in Docker: Flexibility in Data Management</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/data-only-containers-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 08:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/data-only-containers-data-management/</guid>
      <description>We will explore how DOCs (data-only containers), as a deliberate and thought-out approach, for managing data in Docker. DOCs are particularly interesting in scenarios requiring the distribution of static, unmodifiable data – such as packaged website content, tenanted configuration files, or standardized test datasets.&#xA;DOCs offers a reliable and efficient method to manage data separation and portability in Docker to deploy immutable data resources across different stages of development since they can be versioned, shared, and reused across different environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fish Shell: Creating and Sharing Packages with Oh My Fish</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/enhancing-fish-with-omf-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 06:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/enhancing-fish-with-omf-packages/</guid>
      <description>One of the aspects I personally find most compelling about fish shell is its scripting ease. Unlike traditional shells, fish&amp;rsquo;s scripting language is straightforward, clean, and comes with features that encourage writing and maintaining scripts effortlessly. From its intelligent autosuggestions to the robust error handling, fish shell stands out as a powerful tool in the developer&amp;rsquo;s toolkit.&#xA;With the integration of the Oh My Fish (OMF) framework, users can further extend the shell&amp;rsquo;s functionality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse Mosquitto: Leveraging Certificates for Encryption, Identification, and ACLs</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/mqtt_tls_acls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 06:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/mqtt_tls_acls/</guid>
      <description>This blog post delves into the sophisticated use of TLS certificates with Mosquitto, transcending their conventional role as encryption tools to serve as pivotal elements in client authentication and authorization.&#xA;We’ll explore how certificates, typically recognized for their role in securing communications, can be ingeniously repurposed for client identification through their Common Name (CN) attribute. This approach not only enhances the security posture of your MQTT ecosystem but also simplifies the authentication process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Again!</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 19:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>Yes, hello, again! I&amp;rsquo;m trying one more time to get a blog running and keep it up to date, writing about things that interest me. Hopefully, this time will be different and won&amp;rsquo;t be abandoned after a few posts :)&#xA;def hello(): print(&amp;#39;Hello, Again!&amp;#39;) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://calvernaz.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://calvernaz.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>On this blog, I share insights from my journey in technology, sports, and beyond, weaving together my interests in science, politics, and the economy. Join me as I explore the intersections of technology, lifestyle, and continuous personal development.&#xA;I am a software engineer with a passion for building products that make a difference. Reach out to me on GitHub or LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
